<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edgar J. Treischl on Dr. Edgar Treischl</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edgar J. Treischl on Dr. Edgar Treischl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gist</title>
      <link>/project/gist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/gist/</guid>
      <description>The gist package provides a set of functions to work with GitHub Gist &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master SQL with R</title>
      <link>/blog/mastersql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mastersql/</guid>
      <description>This article briefly introduces R packages to master SQL. I will not introduce SQL nor all kind of R packages that are helpful to work with SQL; instead I will focus on packages that support us to learn SQL. First, I show that there is no need to install software, create databases, or get familiar with cloud applications in the beginning. You can focus on and run SQL queries from R with no further ado.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CopyCat</title>
      <link>/project/copycat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/copycat/</guid>
      <description>CopyCat is a small R package to copy, paste, and manage code snippets. CopyCat comes with &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CopyCat</title>
      <link>/workshops/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workshops/test/</guid>
      <description>CopyCat is a small R package to copy, paste, and manage code snippets. CopyCat comes with &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice R</title>
      <link>/publication/practicer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/practicer/</guid>
      <description>Many students learn to analyze data using commercial packages, even though there is an open-source software with cutting-edge possibilities: R, a programming language with countless cool features for applied empirical research. Practice R introduces R to social science students, inspiring them to consider R as an excellent choice. In a non-technical pragmatic way, this book covers all typical steps of applied empirical research. Learn how to prepare, analyze, and visualize data in R. Discover how to collect data, generate reports, or automate error-prone tasks&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Past, Present and Future of Factorial Survey Experiments</title>
      <link>/publication/treischl_wolbring_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/treischl_wolbring_2021/</guid>
      <description>Factorial survey experiments (FSEs) are increasingly used in the social sciences. This paper provides a review about the use of FSEs and aims to answer three research questions. (1) How has this specific research field developed over time? (2) Which methodological advances have been made in FSE research and to what degree are they applied in empirical studies? (3) Which questions remain unresolved and should be addressed in future research? &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gapminder bubble chart</title>
      <link>/dataviz/gapminder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dataviz/gapminder/</guid>
      <description>A remake of the famous Gapminder bubble charts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illustrations</title>
      <link>/dataviz/illustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dataviz/illustrations/</guid>
      <description>Visualizations to illustrate concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streetmap</title>
      <link>/dataviz/streetmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dataviz/streetmaps/</guid>
      <description>A streetmap that visualizes Cologne.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations for Practice R</title>
      <link>/dataviz/practicer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dataviz/practicer/</guid>
      <description>Practice R includes a lot of graphs and illustrations &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create, scan, and correct exams with R</title>
      <link>/blog/examr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/examr/</guid>
      <description>R can be used to create, scan, and correct student exams. This blog introduces the R exams package and shows how the approach works based on demo exam files that come with the package. I demonstrate how R scans exam images, extract answers from single or multiple choice questions, and correct them automatically. Next, I underline typical next steps that are related to this kind of work and how they are implemented in R (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humor</title>
      <link>/dataviz/humor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dataviz/humor/</guid>
      <description> Pie charts are awful, and the Pie charts vs. Pacman underlines this point:
Pie Chart </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical educational research</title>
      <link>/project/ebf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ebf/</guid>
      <description>I held my lecture educational empirical research several times online, inspect &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PythoneeR: Intro</title>
      <link>/blog/pythoneer1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/pythoneer1/</guid>
      <description>I tried to learn Python several times. Once I had a very peculiar class in which we should learn Python for processing natural language. Well, it was more about text mining than applying Python. I tried to learn Python with the help of several books which introduced and ins and out of Python. Before I started to learn Python, I fluently spoke several other statistics software like R, Stata, and please forgive me, my personal journey started with SPSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven Student Advisory and Potential Direct Discrimination</title>
      <link>/publication/sch%C3%B6mer_etal_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sch%C3%B6mer_etal_2021/</guid>
      <description>The use of machine learning found its way into the field of educational research and address the necessity of data-driven student advisory. Notwithstanding the plethora of current research that predicts and quantifies aspects of students&amp;rsquo; academic success in various situations during a student&amp;rsquo;s course of study, most studies focus on the technical aspects and overlook potential of direct discrimination. In addressing this gap, &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Regression App</title>
      <link>/project/olsapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/olsapp/</guid>
      <description>The app shows user with little statistical background the main idea of a linear regression analysis. User can pick &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logistic regression app</title>
      <link>/project/logitapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/logitapp/</guid>
      <description>The shiny app introduces the basics of a logistic regression and examine who survived the Titanic accident &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power App</title>
      <link>/project/powerapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/powerapp/</guid>
      <description>This app introduces power analysis and outlines how sample and effect size are related. Run a &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stata And Paste</title>
      <link>/project/stataandpaste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/stataandpaste/</guid>
      <description>Learn Stata with the help of Stata And Paste. The website (book) provides code to run minimal examples with implemented data &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stata meets R</title>
      <link>/project/statameetsr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/statameetsr/</guid>
      <description>The workshop introduces R for Stata Users and shows the first steps to analyze data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give a Little, Take a Little?</title>
      <link>/publication/2021_treischl_etal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2021_treischl_etal/</guid>
      <description>Given its ability to handle a large amount of data, artificial intelligence (AI) has the potential to improve data-driven decisions under various situations. The present research identifies the necessary conditions for the implementation of an AI-based advisory system (AS) in higher education. Using a factorial survey design, we examine experimentally varied features of an AI-based AS to explore students’ willingness to use it and students’ willingness to share their data as a core challenge for successful implementation &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wirkungsevaluation</title>
      <link>/publication/wirkungsevaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/wirkungsevaluation/</guid>
      <description>Evaluationen werden häufig durchgeführt, um die kausalen Wirkungen einer Maßnahme zu identifizieren. Das Lehrbuch führt in die entsprechenden theoretischen und methodischen Grundlagen der Wirkungsevaluation ein und illustriert diese anhand ausgewählter Beispiele. Ziel des Buches ist es dabei, einen praktischen Bezug zum Ablauf einer Evaluation &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshops empirische Bildungsforschung</title>
      <link>/project/tutzing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tutzing/</guid>
      <description>Dank der Einladung der Akademie für Politische Bildung (Dillingen) durft ich mehrfach die flankierende Lehrgangssequenz &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selection Effects in Students’ Evaluation of Teaching</title>
      <link>/publication/diss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/diss/</guid>
      <description>Student evaluation of teaching (SET) is an empirically well-established instrument for quality assurance in higher education. Most research shows that SET is a reliable and valid instrument to measure teaching quality from students&amp;rsquo; perception and in accordance with Seldins statement one may come to the conclusion, that: &amp;rsquo;the opinions of those who eat the dinner should be considered if we want to know how it tastes&amp;rsquo; (Seldin 1993: 40). However, in many instances students can select courses they want to attend before the course starts, and even in mandatory courses students can often decide how regularly they attend. &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice R</title>
      <link>/project/practicer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/practicer/</guid>
      <description>The Practice R package is the corresponding R package for the book. It contains tutorials, learning materials &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes A A A A A A A A 6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px) Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studentische Lehrveranstaltungsevaluation</title>
      <link>/publication/treischl_wolbring_2017_handbuch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/treischl_wolbring_2017_handbuch/</guid>
      <description>Die studentische Lehrveranstaltungsevaluation (LVE) ist das am weitesten verbreitete Instrument zur Erfassung der Lehrqualität aus studentischer Perspektive. Vor dem Hintergrund des flächendeckenden Einsatzes des Instruments bei gleichzeitig anhaltend starker und weit verbreiteter Kritik gegenüber der studentischen LVE soll der vorliegende Beitrag daher einen  &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Causal Effect of Survey Mode on Students’ Evaluations of Teaching</title>
      <link>/publication/treischl_wolbring_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/treischl_wolbring_2017/</guid>
      <description>In recent years many universities switched from paper- to online-based student evaluation of teaching (SET) without knowing the consequences for data quality. Based on a series of three consecutive field experiments — a split-half design, twin courses, and pre–post-measurements—this paper examines the effects of survey mode on SET. First, all three studies reveal &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selection Bias in Students&#39; Evaluation of Teaching</title>
      <link>/publication/wolbring_treischl_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/wolbring_treischl_2016/</guid>
      <description>Systematic sampling error due to self-selection is a common topic in methodological research and a key challenge for every empirical study. Since selection bias is often not sufficiently considered as a potential flaw in research on and evaluations in higher education, the aim of this paper is to raise awareness for the topic using the case of students’ evaluations of teaching (SET). First, we &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:
Desirée De Leon 🦒 (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)
Garrick Aden-Buie 🧙‍♀️ (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)
Allison Horst 🐕 (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot 🦔)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations for Impact Evaluation</title>
      <link>/dataviz/wirkungsevaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dataviz/wirkungsevaluation/</guid>
      <description>I created several visualizations for the book about &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
